Punic code helper col email to utfa
right so it's like explicitly doing
Punic code um right uh d d encoding I
guess right uh decoding de encoding I
just said encoding decoding I I promise
English is my first language guys um
unod oh my God please stop no
[Music]
all right y' hold up for just a sec
because we've all heard of living off
the land as a red teamer technique right
well unfortunately I just got off a call
with the threat Locker team and they
said that isn't going to fly anymore
thanks to the ring fencing feature let
me double click on that for you okay
think of ring fencing as like an
invisible fence around your applications
as soon as an application interacts with
some app or system resource that it
normally doesn't bam it gets blocked
even if that thing is native to the OS
like powershell.exe or cert util exe so
yeah rip living off the land back to the
drawing board for the red team I guess
anyway if you want to see this in action
head over to threat locker.com for a
demo and when you do ask for my guy
Andrew his demo was very to the point
and he had great answers to all my
technical questions check it out y'all
seriously don't sleep on threat Locker
especially not in this recent landscape
of EDR uncertainty am I right yeah I'm
right okay y'all know all right let's
get back to the
show yo dude all right check this out
check this out I got a good way to start
this episode okay boom space raccoon
pillow you see this boy right here this
is a space raccoon pillow wedding swag
this is wedding swag that's crazy there
was a competition shout out to my boy
Theo who gave this to me there's a
competition at space raccoons wedding uh
for those of you that are listening to a
podcast in audio like a total psychopath
um I am holding up a pillow of space
raccoon one of my favorite hackers out
there and um at his wedding there was a
competition of like you know how well do
you know space raccoon or whatever not
space raccoon you know his name's Eugene
right but I I always call him space
raccoon and um and there's like this
whole thing and unfortunately like our
team didn't win it perfectly because of
like they also showed like vacations
that they'd been on and be like what
city is this I'm like I don't know like
dude we were like Geo
I know dude Pros for like two weeks I
got to I got to give a I got to give a
shout out to um one of the one of the
people on my team because she perfectly
she's like that is the mountains in
Italy and I'm like that is not the
mountains in Italy like we're going
Switzerland we're going France we did
and she was right make this I I cannot
make this up like literally I cannot
make this up okay I use a uh I use a a
Chrome extension uhhuh it's called uh
what is it called
called moment moment or something you
can't tell people what what Chrome
extensions you use man be in your
browser it's called momentum okay it's
like uh when you open a new tab it like
shows you the time and stuff the
background
picture is a lovely mountain
range and at the bottom it tells me
where it's located where is it which is
in Italy oh my gosh dude giving that
dude what was the name of that range I
say no it's not the the colons that's
France H what is what is the mountain
range in Italy that you're seeing maybe
it's the same one let's see uh it's in
giler wow I do not know how to yeah
exactly the gesler Peaks old okay what
the heck that might have been it that's
crazy it was definitely something that
started with a G I can't remember it
right now but um that's quintal anyway I
just had to flex this swag on the people
because there are very few people in the
world that have a space raccoon pillar
and uh I literally went up to Theo and
the guys in the team that won this
afterwards I was like listen guys I need
that you'll understand like I I really
need that like this is serious bragging
rights for me in the security world and
uh and they're like all right sure
Justin whatever take it you know like
all right you need to you need to put a
shelf on your on your back dud I'm going
to find somewhere to put it I I I kind
of want to like put it right by this
monitor here or something like that um
but yeah shout out to my boy Theo I
tried to him with like $100 I was like
man I'll give you $100 USD and he's like
dude just take it like and I'm like
really like so all right all right
that's so um what are we doing today we
are discussing Defcon
research Devcon Devcon not black
hat yeah I mean no I mean there is some
black hat there okay okay yeah but yeah
security summer camp research episode
yeah exactly and there was a lot dude
there was a ton I mean it at this point
it's impossible to like keep up I feel
like yeah but we're going to do our best
to help you guys yeah like maybe like 5
10 years ago you go to Defcon you can
probably see like a lot of the talks now
it's so difficult to see like I mean
there's like three four tracks right
plus the village tracks plus villes were
fire this year man yeah yeah the bug
bunny Mills was awesome there's like a
lot of really good stuff going on so we
met a bunch of people at the bug browny
Village which was really cool um shout
out to the squad we met over there that
was great dude it it this is my first
time you know in Vegas as a content
creator and it's it rocks man people are
always like constantly coming up to you
be like hey it's you and I'm like yeah
who are you you know like and like I
literally I think I had a dream about
that last night where somebody was like
yo techno geek I listen to the Pod and I
was like hello dude it's it we need to
refine our skills on that a little bit
like I feel like I was not prepared
going into Vegas for that and and I I I
need to like learn how to like carry the
conversation and like you know have that
interaction I think it went fine in
general but um you know if I had a weird
interaction with you guys sorry about
that like I wasn't really expecting all
that so um yeah you get to watch a
edited version of one hour of us being
probably as normal as possible dude I
don't know man we've been goofy as heck
the past couple weeks so yeah yeah but
um yeah shout out to to all y'all that
made us feel very special and love to
Devcon really appreciate that that was
great cool meeting everybody we gave out
a bunch of stickers I think we need to
print like five times as many next time
we ordered like what 150 300 stickers or
something like that I think two B 15
yeah we were like a this is going to be
tons and in like five minutes I had like
10 left I was oh God they were gone fast
and we had to start rationing them we're
like all right we're going to take one
pack per day per person you know we I
had to take some for myself because I
was like I'm going to run out of these
before
that's funny yeah we get to the end and
we're like ah my laptop doesn't have a
ctbb sticker on it
like that's funny dude um yeah we also
gave out a bunch of Swag we do have the
swag store live which is great um so
we've got that over at ctbb doow swag so
um check that out if you guys want if
you didn't get one at Vegas um and the
critical thinkers of course get a very
steep discount on the swag so um if
you're a critical thinker in the Discord
then uh check out those that discount
code that's in the exclusive content
Channel um and with that Joel I think we
move into the content um we I have
selected I have selected three four uh
writeups that is pretty much going to be
all we have time for today and we
actually may need to come back and do
like another episode after all the
videos air and stuff like that because
um the ones that we we chose for this
this episode essentially all the ports
sger team um and then orange who we
can't ignore um Port sger team and
orange yeah you know they did really
nice uh like text writeups as well of
their research uh which I really
appreciated um but I'm sure there's a
lot of people that just did videos and
or just did the presentation and didn't
like do a text version as well so I
definitely am looking forward to when
everything comes out where we can go and
watch back some of the other research
yeah absolutely I know a lot of stuff
was live streamed so stuff might certain
things might already be live I I haven't
checked to see oh yeah that's true live
they did live stream this year yeah I
haven't checked to see how many talks
are like split into their own videos and
stuff online yet um or how they're going
to do all that but I think they're
usually pretty quick with it so I would
imagine what was that reaction I I I I I
opened up the Defcon like YouTube
channel and it goes like super loud like
Extremely Loud I think maybe your mic is
down low so I've got you turned up and
then uh I went to this page and it was
like super loud oh man I'll turn myself
up a little bit right now sorry sorry to
our our audio editor yeah sorry sorry
Richard um okay gotcha yeah I mean it
seems like there are some videos up here
so that's interesting we'll have to go
back and uh and try to view some of
those uh in prep for next week but um it
is heavy man the prep is is is heavy for
these Defcon episodes
um uh but mean it's like a full-time job
right like I think in order to educate
people on a topic like this like you
know either you or them has to read
through the entire thing learn it
understand it and then be able to
explain it so it's definitely um it's a
lot of like content consumption to to be
able to like understand the research
yeah yeah for sure okay I'll I'll start
us off with this first one of course
we're going to start off with uh the man
the myth the legend James Kettle in his
research this year um this was on this
is entitled listen to The Whispers web
okay well also hold on let me just go
back for a second I I promise you we
will get to the research but the idea
behind this episode is for us to go
through this research and take the
pieces out that you need to know about
and you can practically integrate into
your hacking methodology and then talk
about those so um I would also recommend
that you go and read all these research
pieces papers and stuff but if you're
just listening to the podcast the hope
is that your hacker brain should be
primed so that when you see something
that relates to this you might think
okay maybe I need to go back and reread
that research or something like that or
maybe you get get some nice takeaways
that you can just integrate into your
methodology as a freebie rather than
having to go and read all this research
so that's the that's the uh that's the
thought for this and with that um listen
to The Whispers web timing attacks uh by
by James Kettle um This research I think
was was really interesting um I think my
take on this is that it's not normal
James quality in my opinion like I think
I think James normally has some stuff
that is extremely like internet breaking
and um
massive right uh and and I think this is
very useful I think this is a useful
tool and he even says this throughout
the the um the the write up he says uh
you know if you ignore timing you're
going to miss out but if you focus too
much on it then you also miss out so I
think I think this is less of a internet
breaking technique like we've seen in
past years um and more of you you just
got to kind of know how to utilize these
timing attacks in the way that he
describes here so that you can exploit
some really Fringe situations in
blackbox scenarios yeah absolutely I you
know I think um one really interesting
thing about not just I mean this isn't
exclusive to james' research but um you
know a lot of this sort of very specific
um specifically scoped research like
these timing attack stuff that he's been
working on for the last however many
years um is what you'll find is that the
large organizations who end up being you
know at a certain point super secure
that's probably where this is going to
start to come into play and the ones who
have secured almost every attack Vector
except for these super weird like Niche
like like architecture specific like
yeah like that's where and it's going to
be super critical right but it's that
that sort of research like has to be
like very targeted and fine point for it
to come out and I think especially you
know with the previous research that
he's done that's helped to secure so
many
as that um you know just naturally this
is going to befic and like harder to
exploit and all that kind of stuff yeah
and and I think he says in the write up
as well like um these things are
everywhere these these timing attacks
but I think you're right in that the
only places where they really need to be
exploited are in these really really
like super Fringe scenarios um and that
being said there there is some some
really cool techniques that we'll talk
about from from this that I I definitely
think you should know about that um are
really amazing and applicable in a lot
of ways um but I you know the actual
exploitation of this at large I think
already requires there to be some sort
of sketchy functionality and then you
are taking that and and building upon it
and using timing attacks to like gain
more information about what's going on
and that sort of thing um so I think
that's really cool I just want to
clarify something I said like this is
100% James quality research like
like the research is very thoroughly
done very well documented um very uh
thorough technique like clearly this guy
is a master researcher right I just I
just you know the stuff that I'm used to
seeing from him is like oh [__] if I do
not implement this right now then uh I'm
going to be missing out big time right
and I think this is like we said more of
an exploitation technique so um with
that let me let me kind of uh go into
some of the stuff that he he did here
that was pretty cool um one of the
things that uh came out of this was dual
packet sync as a as a methodology to um
sort of be close to that single packet
attack that in improve upon the the
single packet attack that he's he had
been using before and essentially what
this new technique uh insures is that
the hgp server doesn't start processing
the hgp headers before it gets the body
because how single packet attack
normally works is you would just SN the
last you know piece of it and uh in one
pack and that would cause everything to
get processed at once but what he
figured out was that some servers were
actually starting to process the HTTP
headers before even before they got the
rest of the the last little uh data
frame from the body and using this
technique um he was able to make it all
sync together so that um everything
including the headers get um get
processed at the exact same time which
is pivotal for this sort of very very
granular type of timing attack that he
talks about in this paper because
because it's like I mean he in one of
the scenarios he was exploting like a
two okay mic two yeah you could call it
nanc but I'm gonna I'm gonna say like 0
2 millisecond difference in some of the
stuff like he's just very consistently
seeing that this one takes just tiny
tiny bit longer um which is just super
badass like uh and and I totally agree
that that like I thought this level of
timing attack was not possible but after
seeing the way that he implements it in
here with with know getting the server
to process it exactly at the right time
um I think it's pretty pretty well
solved I think I think it's I think I
think he's got he's made timing attacks
practical with these tools yeah I mean
it's really cool I think um this has
made me think a bit
about like the efficiency aspects that
go go into a lot of software especially
for like large organizations when you
think about like you know Google for
example like think about how many
requests per second go go has to process
and not only that not just process but
they have to be able to like run it
through other software stack and like
middleware and routing and all this kind
of stuff and they need that to happen in
like two milliseconds right and so there
are certain engineering decisions that
have to be made in order to make a piece
of software that can operate at that
speed and doing stuff like parsing the
headers like as the packets are coming
in are are like the decisions
that lead to these kinds of
vulnerabilities right so I think um that
could probably be a really interesting
research point if somebody wants to like
go deep dive something like Envoy for
example it's like a large scale um like
Edge routing software that's used by a
lot of organizations I wouldn't be
surprised if there is something similar
there because efficiency like is key
when it comes to processing requests
like this yeah yeah and I mean at scale
if you can cut off just a little bit of
time you know in load it it has a
massive impact um and and some of those
things will cause vulnerabilities
inevitably so um the other the other so
two more points here that I that I
wanted to hit um before we talk about
some of the other like more practical
vulnerability stuff that he he um sort
of coined new terms for um one he used a
really cool technique in
here that I think is a little bit odd uh
because of the way that it is but I
think is a cool thing to know about
nonetheless which is he used um he was
trying to detect reverse proxies using
these timing attacks and um he was able
to detect whether DNS resolution like
blocking DNS resolution was occurring um
by using a a DNS record that has an
overlong domain segment um or what is
the um what is the actual technical term
I didn't write it down but essentially
you know uh domain label I believe so
like one of the one of the segments of
the domain right if you make that I want
to say 65 maybe it's 6 yeah greater than
64 so if you make it 65 characters then
it won't even attempt resolution it'll
say hey that's not a valid domain like
I'm not going to touch that right so if
you if you send one that has like 63 or
64 and then you see a certain response
time and you see one that says 65 and
then it's a shorter response time then
you can say with pretty good certainty
that that domain or that DNS resolution
is not occurring and or or is occurring
and then isn't occurring afterwards
right so you can tell that differential
and then use that to determine whether
you're dealing with something that's
actually resolving that that host it
might be a reverse fooxy uh or is not
resolving it it's it's such cool
research because it's like invisible
fingerprinting where it's just like you
know um it's like the next level of
error message like Googling err messages
you know it's like oh this responded in
60 milliseconds it's Apache like
yeah yeah dude it it is it is really
crazy um you know and and I also he uses
a really awesome technique as well and I
think this kind of goes into how um
versatile you should really be as a
hacker and how um various areas of
expertise can apply to hacking in a
really good way he he uses some
statistical analysis on all of these to
make sure that he removes any sort of uh
confounding variables that might be
occurring with like uh spikes and server
load and that sort of thing um by just
using the lower quartile of response
times and he found that that gives him
the best picture um and that's not like
some crazy statistical technique right
like oh I'm like charting it and then
doing this and standard deviation or
whatever but it is like a pretty useful
piece um and I think having that in my
in my brain and knowing like okay well
if I want to you know reduce volatility
in these timing attacks I should use the
bottom cortile of responses because
anything longer than that something else
is happening clearly in the in the
server right because that bottom cortile
is going to represent the fastest that
it's being uh processed um and and so
yeah just kind of having that in my head
and knowing that uh I think is one of
those great little like Boop takeaways
from the paper of like okay if I am
doing timing attacks that's how I should
approach it yeah I mean it's such a
weird thing when you think about just
that like R almost like seemingly
randomly right some requests will just
like go slower or not work because
server load or whatever right server
load like something else is going on
like it's just like it's very you know
we like to think that computers are
super super consistent but uh no they
they're definitely aren't because
there's like so many other external
factors that can affect stuff um which
makes this even just a little bit more
impressive again because like the
Precision that was being done down to
like the nanc on um some of these
attacks is just like crazy crazy it
really is it really is okay so um the
other thing that he had here was uh SC
he he coined a new term which is called
scoped ssrf okay and so this is a new
variant of ssrf sort of uh and this
occurs essentially when you are only
allowed to perform an ssrf to hosts that
are uh in a certain subdomain so let's
say you know I'm attacking Google I can
only hit you know whatever. google.com
right and he coed this term in the
um excuse me on the section of the paper
where he was talking about
how to discover these sort of reverse
proxies right which is very similar to
the research he did many many years ago
um on host header stuff and finding
crazy crazy hosts that you can access by
host headers and he differentiated it um
a reverse proximity from V host scanning
which is V host is just when other hosts
are using that same server um and he
differentiated and said you know this is
sort of a different scenario with
reverse proxies because you've actually
got a server that is a reverse proxy
that is reaching out to a different
server on the internal network based off
of the host header that you're providing
and um one of the cool techniques that
he he did over this this whole piece of
research was essentially building out a
good way to identify these reverse
proxies uh pretty consistently and and
that that is the architectural decision
that they're making using that sort of
DNS trick and some other timing stuff to
identify these reverse proxies in the
organization and then hitting those
reverse proxies a little bit harder with
like vhost scanning or not really vhost
scanning but like host header scanning
right um to see if you can pivot into
different parts of the network um and I
thought that was a really elegant
solution and I think that's something
that I I could easily see like asset Noe
or like some of those people that are
doing very wide scanning and really
wanting UND good understanding of
network topology of their of their
targets um implementing that in like a
microservice or whatever and just saying
okay well XYZ organization has three
reverse proxies they're here here and
here because now we've got a a more
actionable way of actually testing this
um yeah so that that was a big one I
think that was a big one a big take away
from the research and absolutely very
cool yeah super cool I I didn't see
whether or not he called it out but I am
really curious like what the root cause
of that as like the scoped RF stuff is
in terms of like because I know it
mentions just sort of like
misconfiguration of reverse proxy but um
you know from like an absc side it's
always nice to know like what can you
actually fix like how Jo's brain is
spinning like huh reverse do I have a
reverse proxy anyway um yeah so
essentially what it is is when the
reverse proxy is configured to hit any
like Star dot whatever.com right and
then it's it's you know you can pivot
into the internal Network um and abuse
that firewall or that um um what is that
uh DMZ that DMZ position right you know
where that reverse proxy is on the
internet and in the internal Network and
sort of allows for internal pivoting um
but yeah and then he does that right of
course bya that that um timing attack
plus that DNS resolution piece of like
okay if I hit if I see a very
significant statistical difference
between the response of a
64 um character domain label and a 65
then it's a very good chance that there
is some DNS resolution happening that is
taking you know 100 milliseconds or
whatever and that's why we're seeing
that
difference yeah yeah totally I mean
it's it's really crazy I mean and again
it's just like oh it it took 60
milliseconds it's aaty like it's like
it's such like a it's like this
invisible like fingerprinting where
like it what's wrong with it like
nothing's wrong with it how behaves
right yeah and he he says that
throughout the paper he's like yeah
there's not really like a bunch of great
defenses for this you know cuz it's just
how stuff works you know start adding
random uh response delays to every sing
sleep like three it's like the anti
efficiency like just like okay now we're
going to add random amounts of delay so
they can't fingerprint what our systems
are gosh so bad dude but the those are
the worst kind of things right like if
there's literally no fix to this like
what are you going to do you know yeah
yeah so okay last little piece um I was
talking with uh fron and actually I
think probably this episode will air
before the one that that uh we recorded
with fron so um you guys will hear more
about this I think next week um if the
ordering goes right we'll see depends on
how long we run today um but J fron was
recently talking about Json injection
with me and I thought that really
interesting because I don't really hear
a lot about Json in inection and then
James also mentioned uh Json injection
in this research and it just starts
getting you thinking right like two of
the most respected hackers that I know
of right uh are are both talking about
this at the same time and it's not
something that I hear about a lot that's
probably something that should should
trigger some some thoughts right uh so I
don't really know what that looks like
yet um frons seemed to insist in that
episode that there are scenarios where
people are are essentially building Json
blobs with string con concat and you're
able to actually add other attributes
and stuff like that into that Json blob
I have not seen that very often um but
he he insists that it's around and then
James is also mentioning something like
this in in his research um so I just
wanted to put that out there for the
people you know the Curious uh critical
thinking listeners out there that will
also poke and think and you know start
identifying patterns in their targets
because um yeah two two big names are
really interested in that right now so
yeah I mean for sure and just like I'll
say like injection in general I feel is
making a comeback um you know people
used to think of it as like SQL
injection but it's basically I mean it's
the same thing it's just in all the
other Technologies right so okay you're
building a Json object yep Json object
injection right you're concatenating a
string you can escape that property with
like an ending quote and then start to
add new properties in um graph kill
injection like again like building
quaries with string concatenation like
string concatenation and just inserting
strings without sanitizing them or
without having like a proper flow right
like the traditional solution for SQL
injection is prepared statements which
like pre-calculates a path so you have
to figure out like what is
the that that what is the the the
prepared statement for Json right like
you build the object and then you
specifically like go attribute by
attribute or something right like you
know there there are ways to do it but I
think in a lot of places people got have
gotten lacks because there's not a
traditional security risk associated
with it and people go I mean what's
wrong with concatenating a string in a
Json object like what's going to happen
well you know maybe you're able to pass
that into a function that then
interprets those as parameters and you
know you're able to overwrite parameters
or add additional options that weren't
you know without without um you know
talking too much about Fran's research
for next episode like that that's EX
that he was talking about like being
able to inject in these sort of trusted
Json blobs and then be able to overwrite
specific pieces specific attributes
because of like d duplication of
attributes and that sort of thing um
very interesting stuff very interesting
stuff uh very cool I I I'll definitely
be paying more attention to scenarios
where I think that could be occurring
and uh we we'll see where that goes over
the next couple
years um all right that's all I had for
James's research you have anything else
on on that I don't think so I mean
hopefully hopefully we did it justice um
I mean it's definitely worth giving it a
read so if you're unsure about anything
that we said or wanted some more
clarification go check out the uh the
article on the ports sger research page
yeah absolutely I I know James listens
so James I'm sorry if I messed something
up man like forgive me but oh master of
security research like uh but I think uh
I think it was good all right where you
want to go next because we're pretty
much hitting the
let me just pause and also say like the
port swiger team crushed it this year
with research um and and really like
we're gonna spend pretty much this whole
time talking I should probably title
this episode like Port swiger research
you know brain dump or something like
that because like it's pretty much all
ports research and then we're going to
talk a little bit about orange at the
end um yeah I mean I don't know how many
talks they submitted but I know they had
at least these three yeah that got
accepted so impressive I mean it just
goes to show that there's a lot of
really awesome research going on over
over at ports Wier right yeah where
where do you want to go next you want to
do the the uh gotta gotta cash them all
or do you want to do the splitting the
email Adam let's do the splitting the
email that one's really cool all right
cool um you want to take that one or
should I um well let's let's let's take
it together so um This research was from
Gareth Gareth Hayes we' talked about in
inventor of hack verter um inventor of
Shazer Shazer
um which I think just released you can
now use your friends browsers to like
fuzz your JavaScript angas or something
I don't know pretty cool he tweeted
something out about that but um
basically this this research all centers
around um the email format RFC which is
what RFC 2822 I think uh is what it says
so basically it just talks about like
you know rfc's are really interesting
and and I think probably at least once a
year there's there's some sort of talk
at either Conor black hat about an RFC
that is um not being interpreted
correctly or is being interpreted too
correctly um or maybe it was written in
a way such that there are pitfalls that
nobody really thinks about um and so I
think email address parsing is
definitely uh probably one of the bigger
ones right um I mean this has been
talked about for a while um I think I
want to say Z shaana was the one who
really made that popular initially putss
payloads in I saw him talk about it but
for me the first interaction with this
was um in in's research on it back in
the day and then um you know with with
ticket trick and a bunch of other stuff
like that and then um I know uh Roan
also took it for a little while and did
some stuff with it so there's been
there's been a lot of people that have
poked at this uh email RFC and Gareth
comes in and like blows our minds with
more of that so something something says
that 's probably more to be discovered
in the in the email research realm yeah
yeah I mean if if nothing else this uh I
I know that he had to update this
article actually afterwards and he was
like oh yeah I had some extra uh some
bonus material that I added to the end
of this that were like some more
injection payloads that were like worked
in more specific scenarios and like yeah
I mean it's uh it's really crazy
research so what is it um so basically
the a lot of it boils down to the fact
that there are certain characters that
you can that are valid in an email
address uh especially in the like first
part of the email address um before the
at symbol that end up either being
transformed or interpreted or parsed in
a way that allows you to do way more
than just provide an email so oftentimes
you know a lot of this was ending up as
like SMTP injection um changing like the
SMTP directives or commands that were
being put in like a raw email
like text or command or whatever that's
getting sent to the email server um so
yeah I mean it's really really cool
research I think one of the one of the
coolest things um was this whole like
equals question mark encoding thing yeah
dude I freaking love that part encoded
word or whatever right yeah yeah yeah
RFC 2047 another RFC very good very good
it's called encoded word yeah and it's
like this encoding system that um allows
to write uh encoded characters is like
hex and it's like so foreign because if
you look at this screenshot you're like
what what the heck is this like I've
never this is a thing like what what is
this what is this thing and yeah
apparently it is a thing you can like
send hex encoded characters like an
email address in like this raw format
that like tells it here's the character
set um and here's like the data and then
it ends up decoding it uh
somewhere I'm GNA actually gonna paste
this this image into the doc really
quick and make a note for Richie uh add
this to the screen if possible so for
any of you uh watching on YouTube
hopefully that will be up on the screen
right now um but essentially Joel when I
saw this I was super triggered because
uh I did a Defcon talk back in 2022 with
Sam herb essentially an exploitation
story of how we popped this Enterprise
software but it had some crazy parts to
it and one of the crazy Parts was um
this sort of encoding that you see right
here which starts with like equals
question mark uh and then you provide
like the encoding type and then you do
another question mark and then you just
essentially start writing the text you
want with equal sign and then the hex
value equal sign hex value equal sign
hex value um this also works in HTTP
headers man and so you can literally
yeah hold on let me let me let me link
you to this presentation I'm like cuz I
I saw this and I I was like I was impr
pre for this episode and I was super
triggered because I was like oh my gosh
why didn't I look deeper into this and I
sent a message to Gareth and I was like
dude have you seen this and he's like
whoo I didn't like that can be done in
HP headers as well um so there's
definitely some cool applications for
smuggling with this uh I just sent it to
you on on Discord but um this this type
of encoding with the equal sign and the
question mark my God in cherry pie yeah
exactly in Cherry Pie um is is a is a
common way it seems for various internet
systems especially the stuff that was
created way back in the day like
original HTTP protocol and original SMTP
to encode values that may not have a
super clean um utfa or asky
representation right um and and so he's
using that again here to essentially get
these emails to have sort of malicious
characters in them which then get misp
parsed by either the application layer
or by more impactfully via the actual
SMTP server that's sending all this
stuff out um which is is genius really
dude it's uh that's really really
interesting that like that is
specifically in the code I actually went
and I looked too and it's still there
yeah uh I don't know like when you made
this slide but yeah sure looks uh did
they fix something or no no there's
there's not you know I was gonna say
yeah CU it I think it still I hit up
Cher cherrypy and chery was like No And
then engx was like that's Cher y's
problem and then and then they just so
it's one of those you know mismatches
again where it's like
um engine X doesn't see it doesn't parse
uh this sort of uh what is it I ISO
[Music]
8859 they literally use decod header
from email. header yeah yeah so so
that's not fixed in in cherrypy and
there was probably other um other HTP
servers that also support this ISO
8859-1 um encoding type and then there's
also this sort of same sort of thing in
uh emails apparently um where a valid
email can have like a bunch of question
marks and a bunch of like hex encoding
and then when the email actually gets
sent you know it'll get sent to whatever
the asky representation of that is so
I'll just I'll I'll give our listeners
the benefit of the doubt here that they
can maybe visualize this okay guys
listen listen closely so this this email
looks like equal sign question mark utf8
question mark Q question mark and the
asky representation in HEX so for
example ABC would be 61 62 63 so it's
equals 61 equals 62 equals 63 at
whatever.com and then when the email
actually gets sent it gets sent to ABC
whatever.com um and so it's it's really
odd um and I think this is the main I
think you successfully identified Joel
like this is the main takeaway right
like from this whole thing because if
you look at all of the exploits that he
has in in that that write up all of them
take advantage of encoded word so a
really a really easy probe that you can
throw out there really quick is just
have your email in encoded word and send
that in and if you get the email then
okay there might be something a little
bit easier to to you know or this is an
easy way for you to identify that this
is something you need to look at a
little bit deeper right and I think one
of the big ways that he was able to take
advantage of this was around
like Auto invite stuff as well right so
like the the this is basically
everywhere yeah it's like in encoding
bypass for like email especially which
is then used in a lot of different
places so like um say you a a work slack
and anybody who signs up for that slack
with the company domain email gets
automatically added to the
workspace well you encode your email and
encoded word and the front end goes oh
no this is a this is a different domain
and then the email system interprets it
completely different and it ends up
going and like registering it your
account to you know restricted domain
that you might not have access to and
now you have access to you know this
company slack that you shouldn't have
access to and I think that this I don't
think slack was actually a specific
example I think GitHub or hold up Joel
hold up hold up don't say anything stop
saying words man like I literally while
we're writing this I like wrote down a
couple targets that I know do this and
I'm like cuz literally I get back from
Devcon I was sick then I like and had
some stuff going on for a week and now
this is my first week back from Defcon
and the first thing I do is go read all
the research and like prep for this
episode and I'm finally done with that
and now I'm ready to do some freaking
hacking so don't say any of the targets
that have this because I'm GNA go try it
right after this and uh yeah we'll see
I'll keep you guys updated if I make any
money off of it but if you know any but
you're right man like any any Target
that has the sort of implicit Trust of
email domain um we need to try this on
like
100% a one Joel Joel stop it please
God okay fine whatever I won't go after
that one um all right sweet so uh let's
see lots of other takeaways from this
one man uh I'll I'll take the next one
here
um so one of the ways that he so encoded
word isn't isn't going to solve your
problem there has to be encoded word
plus some other Quirk right so there's a
couple ones that he mentioned here um
and one of them we we see is called uucp
one of them is called Source routing one
of them is called uh Unicode overflow so
I I'll start at the top Unix to Unix
copy uu CP is a super whack protocol and
uh this protocol essentially allows you
to provide a this is my tldr of the
situation you know having having read
over it essentially this allows you to
provide address an address for this sm2p
interaction in this Unix Unix copy
address format which has the
domain before the actual user
information which is the inverse of
email right the domain goes at the end
for email so essentially what he the way
he discovered this and I love how humble
he is about the way he he describes the
way that he found this because he is
like yeah I just like jammed a bunch of
characters into this thing and all of a
sudden I saw that I was getting like an
invalid host resolution
and and apparently he put a exclamation
point character and backslash escaped
the at symbol just by Chance in This
setup and then he like had the good
sense to like go and actually figure out
why that was happening and then stumbled
upon this vulnerability um but
essentially this protocol allows you to
specify a destination for this SMTP um
interaction that is not in the
traditional format and you can specify
the domain first then a exclamation
point that is your delimiter for the
domain and then a bunch of other
information and if and then use a
backslash to escape the at sign um so
that it isn't interpreted as an email
address so the front end uh application
layer might think that this is an email
address ending in you know at
example.com but actually this is a uu CP
address um that is that's domain is
actually what is before the exclamation
point um which is just
sick like absolutely sick it's like such
a weird weird thing and it makes me
wonder now like maybe I need to go pick
the brain of like somebody who like used
Linux in like 1985 exactly be like hey
like uh tell me about like all the
annoying things you had to work around
and tell me how that worked what is this
uucp thing like yeah yeah super I just
need to ask them like do you know what U
CP is and if they know what it is then
I'm just going to be like okay have like
eight more questions for yeah exactly
that's like the delimiter question like
okay yes okay sit down you
know that's great um yeah so and I want
to say that this uucp thing was
enabled by default on like post what was
it postfix is that I think it was
postfix yeah yeah dude it's like it's
pretty bad that this sort of stuff yeah
it was postfix it's like what is going
on here um that this is still like a a
functional protocol and this SMTP seems
so disjointed from a lot of the stuff
that like when I think about the
application layer I don't really include
the SMTP server in that right like it's
it's different yeah I mean it's one of
those technologies that is extremely old
I mean like literally like I remember
like taking like a intro to networking
class and like opening netcat and you
connect to an smtb server and you go
like eh and it's just like replies back
you know like it's completely text based
protocol it's like very very like simple
it's it's similar to http in that sense
right yeah um 100% And and also I need
to correct something Joel the um the
uucp protocol was not uh on on postfix
postfix has a different thing which
we'll talk about in a second The Source
routes but um send mail
8.15 two is uh is the vulnerable
configuration that he was using when he
discovered this so those are the two
main SMTP you know I think there's
another one but uh he actually does say
that postfix actually supports uucp as
well oh yeah he says it later right um
yeah yeah with the I think it
was no it's actually pretty early on oh
I later found out that if you use the
single parenthesis trick uh postfix also
supports uucp okay yeah yeah so send
mail and mind blown man send mail and
postfix both support this like ancient
thing um which is pretty pretty amazing
um so that was that was one of the main
takeaways there is like there there's a
bunch of so at a more concrete level
remember this whole uucp trick with the
exclamation point in back uh SL escaping
the at sign when you're dealing with um
anything SMTP related and then taking
this concept a little bit bigger
whenever you have sort of tangental
systems to your application layer right
like maybe your application layer in
this situation he like shits on Ruby a
lot so maybe your application layer in
Ruby right and then you've got some
other thing you're interacting with like
a like an SMTP server like that sort of
thing um you got to think about what
that second degree what other sort of
weird configurations and what kind of
other weird protocols and variants that
other piece deals with um because I
think we've seen that pattern of dealing
with these sort of out of band um
entities and them supporting some weird
old [__] that we can exploit yeah yeah
absolutely I mean it it a lot of it is
just like the backwards compatibility
stuff and it's just been baked in and
never removed and you know it's like why
does Cherry Pie support that encoding
like who knows who knows like yeah yeah
yeah um okay next one is Source routing
this one was another really cool old
Legacy variant um and specifically
within Source routing the percent hack
and essentially uh what this allows you
to do is specify multiple domains that a
specific uh entity should be sent a
specific SMTP interaction should
communicate with um in one address which
is like perfect for this sort of thing
right like it's just it's perfect um and
how it works is you can specify for
example like ABC and then you do percent
sign rat.com at example.com right so the
application lever layer is going to see
that as an example.com uh email address
and give you access to like everything
that's associated with that you know in
your organization or whatever but when
that specific domain gets passed to an
SMTP server that supports this sort of
source routing percent hack scenario it
will send the email first to ABC
example.com
then to ABC reator.com essentially
cutting off the the at sign at the end
and then replacing the the next percent
sign with a an at sign and then sending
the email there so the actual like
validation email that might get sent out
would go to like ABC rat.com which is
perfect because then you can snag that
code yeah you know very um intuitive
Behavior everybody would expect like
this is obviously how this is supposed
to work yeah
like perfect user experience why does
this exist man it's crazy um I thought
that was amazing though I thought that
was like literally like a dream come
true scenario for hackers right it's
like I think one interesting thing about
that for me is like I'd love to know if
anybody's actually legitimately using
this
like probably not and if so who and why
like it's time to retire if that's the
case I'm really curious like how much of
this is just like Legacy garbage that's
just been like you know kept in because
of the spec or you know who knows what
or if it's just like you know there's
secretly like the entire banking system
is using Source routing or
something yeah yeah for sure okay so
we've got so so far we've got
uucp uh we got encoded word uucp and
Source routing um another takea away
from this one was this whole concept of
Unicode overflows which I think was this
one and uh Punic code which is something
we're going to talk about in a second I
think I felt like were like little
bonuses to the actual um email research
like a lot of the stuff here that we
just talked about was like and I found
this in the the RFC and this is cool and
then the unic code stuff and the Punic
code stuff are both like wow this is
some cool like asky management uh or
like Unicode to asky conversions and
normalization that are occurring and
then we can weaponize this in the email
Arena but we can also weaponize this in
other areas um so listen here listen
closely here for these next couple of
ones if you are are not even if you're
not necessarily interested in email
related hacking because well and also
like real quick I love that something
finally is able to exploit Punic code
because Punic code is one of those
things that where you know you're like
testing like domain registar you know
all these different things usually it's
like for ssrf and you know you input a
domain and you're trying character like
bypasses and you try like you know some
weird car set and it turns it into a
punicode domain you're like Ah that's so
annoying well there might actually be
something there now yeah absolutely and
I'm looking I didn't actually put a
bunch of um uh I didn't write a bunch of
notes on the whole Punic code part so
maybe you can explain that one or I can
take a stab at it real quick um but the
unic code piece was really interesting
uh
because the Unicode overflows this this
is goes into how Unicode is being
processed and how um I guess even
specific asy related stuff is is being
processed because essentially what it
what it would do and he just noticed
this while he was I think blackbox
testing and was getting weird characters
out of putting um aski um or Unicode
into a place where the application
expected aski essentially what was
happening here was they were taking the
Unicode Cod point and they were just
running like mod to 56 on this so any
any you know Unicode thing that would
mod to 40 right if you if you R took the
code point and then ran mod on it to and
to give you the output there anything
that would convert to 40 including like
this weird l and a bunch of other
characters would get normalized to an at
sign um and then he was able to use that
to like mess with some of the parsers um
for emails and and kind of split the the
whole the whole research is called
splitting the email atom and so the co
concept is like splitting the the email
domain where it shouldn't be or getting
things delivered to invalid locations
because of that um and he was able to
use these Unicode overflows to do that
and I think we'll see this 100% we'll
see this in other areas I want to even
say file descriptor has an xss out there
somewhere on Twitter um that utilized
something similar to this um and it's
not just wasn't something that was on my
radar uh actively until Gareth brought
this back to my attention yeah
absolutely yeah so so for the for the
puny code thing um very similar type of
you know issue basically where like you
could force it to decode improperly so I
guess this was a bug in the PHP idn
Library um that would be used to decode
Punic code itself and you could
basically just generate like arbitrary
characters in Punic code encoding by
like writing them in this certain
specific format and um you know putting
I think it was just like two zeros
before I discovered that if you use two
zeros at the start at the start you
could generate unintended characters
with Punic code yeah yeah so with this
now you can have like valid domain quote
unquote right but when it gets decoded
with like puny code is encoding it's not
like a domain I mean it is for domains
but right but like decoding it and
having it be a valid domain are two
separate things right and so basic
basically he was able to generate Punic
code valid strings that decode to
invalid domains with like commas and ATS
symbols and stuff like that that should
never be in a Punic code domain and then
when that would be used within like the
SMTP protocol or like you know in this
specific scenario in the in the actual
application layer when it was displaying
that email on the screen for the user to
see right exactly yeah so jumla I
believe this was was was the big example
so jum jumla was you know doing Punic
code decoding on your email address so
that it would render properly in the web
but you know again you can inject non
Val like invalid email characters into a
valid puny code string and so when this
gets decoded now you have essentially X
well HTML injection which can lead to
xss so um I think he was able to
escalated all the way to rce apparently
I think through template um no injection
it was through CSS injection um and it's
an interesting escalation to RC because
despite all of his attempts here to
generate um a valid xss payload with
with Punic code it seems like it is not
possible um to get that to actually do
it he he him and uh Gareth and also some
of the other members of the POR sger
research team spent a decent amount of
time it says um kind of poking around
with this and couldn't couldn't get it
to generate like a valid xss payload but
what he was was able to get it to do was
generate a um an opening style tag and
then he was able to utilize the way that
that style tag was placed um adjacent to
another injection point that he had um
to essentially be able to trigger a
arbitrary uh CSS import um it's like an
xss with two injection points right you
have like one variable and you you start
your payload so it doesn't get fully
filtered out in the second variable you
finish your payload and there's a bunch
of in the middle but doesn't really
matter because you have the start and
the end that builds out a full payload
that that actually succeeds exactly yeah
and so then you know of course I love
this with Gareth right like he's like
all right well we're in a CSS injection
context no problem and then he like
whips out whips out like where is this
where's the thing he's like um so we
needed now to exfiltrate the C csrf
token via uh CSS thankfully there have
been many good posts on this and the
best way to do it is import chaining uh
as mentioned by donut in uh Pepe V and
and I decided to use I however decided
to use the custom or customize the tool
that I already developed for my blind
CSS injection research um which is just
super badass and that tool Is Amazing by
the way so dude and it's so funny
because as I was reading this I was I
was thinking before I got to the end of
that like paragraph I was like huh I
wonder if he if that was like a sneak
peek like oh yeah here's the CSS
injection tool and then behind the
scenes he was like doing all this stuff
and he wrote that tool just for this
no it it's actually completely separate
research that just like ended up being
perfect yeah he's like and I'll release
that and then a couple months later I'll
drop that no so that's great and and I
love seeing CSS inject injection explo
uh exploited in a really effective way
here um I think in the end that this
would still because it's just a um a uh
SE surf token
exfiltration uh I think that it still
requires user interaction to pop this uh
rce um but you know such as life man I
think it's still an rce one click rce is
better than zero click I mean wait uh
one click RC is better than uh no RC RC
okay and I think um I think also that
there's potential to get this to um to
zero click um we just need to sort of
crack this this puny code um nut where
we essentially it just will not generate
the correct characters for any sort of
excess related payLo and he's able to
get it to to generate um SVG like an SVG
tag I just don't think that it can get
to the point where it actually like has
the correct event handler and doesn't
have junk text in between so right yeah
and I mean I don't know how thorough
like how deep Gareth went with this and
if he just stopped at the phpn library
but one thing I remember vividly from
one of Orange's earlier talks uh around
URL parsing uh
was
the wide expansive libraries that were
tested and how many were vulnerable
across like different languages
different implementations like different
commonly used like you know here's this
python Library here's this Ruby Library
here's this PHP library and so I I would
be really curious to see how many other
things are affected like this like
cherry pie like you know large HTTP
framework library that is used by a lot
of things like just randomly supports
this
uh word encoded word stuff like you know
same thing like how is the puny code
library for python doing Punic code is
it also V vulnerable in the same way um
and how many other you know web services
and stuff could you affect in that way
yeah absolutely and and I think it's
kind of odd here because the the jumla
code that's used specifically says Punic
code helper col colon email to utfa
right so it's like explicitly doing puny
code um uh de de encoding I guess right
uh decoding de encoding I just said
decoding decoding I I promise English is
my first language guys um UND encod oh
my God please stop so no um and so uh I
think I think this is something that
will probably not happen super um
implicitly I think it's probably
something that'll be more implicit
throughout applications but that doesn't
mean that we can't still poke for it
especially when you have Source like
source code it might be helpful even to
start looking for like oh where's Punic
code mentioned in here and how does that
why does it work that way so um yeah
very cool stuff there um I don't think
there's anything else on that one so
we'll call that a wrap on splitting the
email Adam um next up is gotta cash them
all and wow we might have a new we might
have a new little tagline dude we might
have to just throw that in there it's
catchy man it it's good I like I really
liked it
um I think I think you you said your
favorite research was the email research
right yeah yeah that was super cool and
I think this one is your favorite right
it is it is I think this is the one for
me and the reason for this is like wow
um one I wasn't as familiar with uh I
believe it's Martin right it probably
it's pronounced differently but Martin's
research um in the past I haven't seen
much from him and I was I was really
impressed with this research and there I
I think that a lot of the techniques
that he talked about
here were pretty known to the people
that really know a lot about webcast
deception and webcast poisoning um which
by the way for me like timing attacks
and web cash poisoning are like the two
like they're like Quantum Computing to
me bro it's like we got I understand
like you know how it works and stuff but
it's like like such like a weird like
deep sort of attack scenario that like
you really have to like be at a certain
level with the application to be like hm
yeah there's some like there's some like
caching stuff and then like
understanding how you can actually
exploit them in different level of like
intimacy with the application is that
what you say I was AO I was avoid again
but yes come on just lean into it man
that's that it's a catch face man um
yeah so I I think this research was
really good because what he did is he
did the leg work he did the leg work for
everything he went and he like this
whole research is filled with um like
these Graphics that show how different
um systems you know Cloud flare
cloudfront Azure gcp Apache enginex how
all of these things process various uh
permutations uh on uh dot segments right
so path reversals um uh origin and cach
level delimiters like it's awesome and
and
he doesn't just say like hey sometimes
this works he says this works on this
this this this this and this and there's
incompatibilities between this and this
and this and this and this and this
right and I just I love that like that
is also I just want to shout out how
much of a grind that is because you know
what he had to do was like go and spin
up each one of these services and like
configure that [__] and that is boring
stuff right that is not exciting
security research but especially when
you spend like three hours spinning one
of them up testing it and then it
doesn't work and you just go no on your
spreadsheet and then you go to the next
one exactly exactly man like it's not
even excited you're like oh now I have
50 things I can exploit it's like oh D
okay exactly the next one so major props
to him for putting in the leg work and
getting this research in place um and
there were some some pieces that I was
not familiar with just in my own
methodology in here so so Props to him
for that um and let's kind of talk a
little bit about those okay um so this
whole this whole thing is about about
practical applications of these research
right so with with um with the research
from James you know we we're paying
attention to these attacks we're
understanding how to use that domain um
label length with Gareth stuff we're
checking for encoded word we're checking
for some of these weird Fringe things uh
once we have identified that we have
something funky here or maybe if we're
interested in email level authentication
and with uh this cach related stuff man
there's a lot of takeaways dude like
there fingerprinting your your target
will now give you so much of an insight
into what is actually happening uh
because of of the research that he's
done here um so first I need to to make
I'm sorry I'm going to rant a little bit
here Joel can I like can I cook for a
second like go go for it let them cook
the apron's coming on like I got the
chef hat I'm ready to go um so uh in the
talk he he defines multiple different
types of delimiters he talks about
origin delimiters cache delimiters
front-end delimiters and backend
delimiters depending on the context
right and there's two different types of
of of caching related bugs there's
there's um web cach deception which
requires user interaction and there's
webcache poisoning which doesn't require
user interaction okay so um and I think
the visuals that he had in the
presentation and also in the actual um
you know write up on on the ports
website really really good for
understanding so Joel if you are trying
to get a better understanding of this
you know giving that thing a twice twice
three times over might might really
clear that up for you um and so the
concept of origin delimiters is like the
backend server right like we're thinking
about we've got a caching server in
front and then we've got the origin
server um those are delimiters in the
path that happen only on the origin
server and not on the cache server right
so he gave a bunch of examples of these
uh the one that's really common that we
that a lot of us know about from the
research that orange date a couple years
back is the semicolon right that being
used in in Spring environments in Tomcat
I think as well to delimit like a path
parameter or a matrix parameter um so
the difference between that being parsed
as part of the path and it not being
parsed as part of the path can mean the
difference between um what extension is
used uh appears to be in place um at the
caching level and at the origin level um
so let's say if the caching server is
caching everything that ends injs right
or css then we can say SL myy account
userinfo
semicolon. CSS right and the back end
when it's processing that won't even pay
attention to that that that semicolon
part because it's a parameter it's like
if you had put a question mark right uh
but the but the front end the caching
server sees that as a path ending injs
or css or whatever and says oo I need to
cach that um and he lists in the
research um like cloudflare has I
believe it's cloudflare uh yeah Cloud
flare has like this list of extensions
uh 7z Avi doav if. APK like Cloud flare
by default cashes all of these if they
if it ends in this so which I guess
makes sense right like from a CDN
perspective like most of those at least
the ones that you listed are like you
know media files like you have to
remember like CDN their business is
bandwidth traffic right and so like the
more traffic the more that costs them
and the more they have to serve that
file over and over again the more it
costs them so their whole goal is going
to be to serve that file as few times as
possible uh and if it ever gets updated
update as few times as possible yeah
absolutely they're definitely
incentivized to go down that path so it
does make sense but it definitely causes
some BS so um understanding what origin
delimiters you have in your environment
is pivotal to to being able to trigger
web cach deception and and webcache
poisoning but he calls it um the delimit
or something different in that way um so
let me just run through these really
quick so you got the the semicolon for
spring and like Tomcat you've got the
dot for rails which is really
interesting because I didn't know this
about I didn't know this sort of
tangentially about rails but it hadn't
really concreted in my brain if you're
if you're dealing with a rails
environment um you can add Dot and then
whatever at the end and it'll still show
you the same result in a lot of ways and
I didn't really know why that was and
the reason it is is it's looking for
it's taking that dot and it's trying to
decide what view to display in rails and
if the dot doesn't have if that
extension that you provided after the
dot doesn't have a registered
view then it will just show you the
default view which is such an amazing
functionality right um and so there are
differences this is one of the things
that was in the presentation that wasn't
in the actual research um that paper
that he showed um was that if you if
there are select set of um Cloud flare
caching extensions that uh are are not
also valid rails uh extensions so rails
won't even like if you try to give it I
forget one of I did I think I
screenshotted it or took a picture of it
on my phone or whatever but like maybe
it's like Tiff or something like that
right rails will never serve a you know
that uh but CER will always cash that
right if it's if that's at the extension
so rails is g to fall back to the
default view and show you whatever it
normally does um while still having that
that do Tiff extension and then Cloud
flare will be like oh that's atiff file
so I got to Cache
that so weird it's rad dude it's
freaking rad I mean again it's like
these weird intricacies of um Frameworks
right it's not even just like
necessarily sing singular application
vulnerabilities it's like common
configurations of things that are tied
together
like
Apache
and some web server behind it and like
reverse proxies cashing proxies all
these right exactly yeah so it's so
interesting okay couple more he listed
um n bite for open light speed which I
haven't seen quite as much of open light
speed but I mean if he put it on there
it's probably decently sized um and then
percent O A for engine X rewrite rules
which has got to break a ton of things
man like if percent OA is truncating the
path Onix rewrite rules like that has
got to break a ton of things so um that
wasn't one that I was super using often
in my uh web cash deception uh checks so
that is definitely one that I'll be
adding um and to be honest what he
recommended in that scenario is just
like hit everything in asky range just
give it a shot you know try it encoded
try it not encoded try it double encoded
and see if there's any differential
between the two um so I might just make
a massive list of every asky character
every encoded asky character and then
every double encoded asky character and
just whenever I have a suspicion about
any of this just like throw that whole
list at it and look for the outliers
yeah I mean that's what I was going to
suggest because I mean like you said
like none of this is like necessarily
new research um but I think it's like a
great sort of like reference uh to have
like you know if you come across you
know some um some cash poisoning then
take a look at this article and go
through and be like okay okay let me try
this this this until something works or
you can just do what you said and have
that list of all the characters fuzz
everything and something will work
probably I mean if you have a if there's
an issue there yeah and I think there
are some new pieces of research in here
just to be clear but like this this this
specific set I think has been I'm not
sure if it's known publicly but at least
known within the like people that
actively exploit webcast deception and
and other stuff environment just being
like trading this tip with your friend
or whatever that sort of thing um
uh and but it's just nice to see it
formalized you know um and then
so as far as cach limiters goes so
something that the caching server thinks
is a delimiter that isn't a delimiter on
the on the backend server um there's not
a lot of them besides like maybe
question mark sometimes if it's encoded
and passing along the encoded value or
the unencoded value the unencoded why do
I do this the decoded value um un UND
encoded just just just I why do I do it
I don't know um uh but he he had a great
Point switching from webcash deception
to web Cas poisoning which is a non-user
interaction required attack where you
poison cached assets for other users um
that the hashtag can really cause some
Havoc uh and essentially the cach server
seeing that uh as a delimiter in the
backend knot or vice versa right um and
since we're not having we're not limited
by the browser having to force the user
to make a request in their browser we
can send like the hashtag in an hgp
request to the server in just directly
with like burper kaido and then see how
that actually gets processed and and how
whether the caching server discards it
at the cashing server level or whether
it gets um
dis considered to be a part of the path
at the origin level um and there's
there's an once again another great uh
graph in here that is just like blowing
my mind of the the amount of variance
between whether hashtag is a delimiter
in these various um entities right so
Cloud flare no cloudfront yes gcp error
Azure yes impera no Apache error engine
X yes uh open light no like spring eror
rails yes jeno no like it's like
everything parses this differently oh
man um and so you know what would be
awesome like follow-up research from him
was would be like some sort of just like
simple Docker like a repo with like 15
Docker containers in it you just like
spin them all up and then you can just
like send one request all of them that
is
called HTTP Garden whoa and actually I
met the guy uh I met the guy who wrote
this um at the the Google Live hacking
event in Vegas and and I like didn't
know who he was dude this is sick and I
I was like hanging out with him and then
is a collection of HTP servers and
proxies configured to be composable
along with scripts to interact with them
in ways that makes vulnerabilities much
much easier that's awesome dude it's
awesome man and I was like talking to
him about it and I was like hey you know
have you like heard of HP Garden or
whatever he's like yeah I wrote that and
I'm like what like are you kidding me
you're the guy that wrote H Garden CRA
like literally literally like you just
like give it a payload and like like
with the SLR sln and it just prints out
a freaking tape yeah also dude this guy
that wrote this Ben is his name um let
me see if I can find yeah Ben Callis it
was so funny cuz we were like hacking
together at the at the live hacking
event or whatever and just like sharing
interesting leads and stuff and I was
like yeah so just open up like kaido or
open up burp or whatever and he's like
what and I'm like open up those and he's
like oh I don't use that I just uh I use
print F and netcat dud and I'm like what
and it's so funny too dude if you look
if you look in the like read me for for
HP Garden you see a bunch of stuff like
that like he's clearly very used to just
writing hgp requests by hand on the
command line like a total badass like
and um and so this is like payload it's
like get SL HTP 1.1 backr back host a
backr like one ler HTP request um so
anyway shout out to Ben DG rock thank
you for developing this this tool that
that allows us to um test a bunch of HTP
servers and proxies really really easily
um also maybe learn how to use Bur
but also let me just say like he also he
also told me he's like yeah I mean cuz
like this is the ultimate level of
control right there's no weird like
parsing error and burp or like nothing
everything you write is like you
intentionally wrote that character which
is great and I can see how that would be
really helpful in like um HB request
smuggling which I think he does a lot of
and other stuff like that um but man for
like testing idors that that sucks you
know like um so yeah very cool research
there and yeah that that does exist Joel
already I will
say probably the most interesting thing
I mean other than everything else but
what has really caught my eye on this
HTP guard read me is under the
acknowledgement section it says this m
this material is based upon work
supported by the the defense Advanced
research projects agency DARPA under
contract number HR 00111 19c
76 wow dang dude all right thanks DARPA
just thanks DARPA darpa's doing HTTP
server research that's appreciate that
dude apparently there's like a major
DARPA AI competition or something like
the AI cyber challenge that's like
something like $4 million is the number
one prize or something like that dude
what yeah it's kind of nuts I think this
is more like Ming up exactly I think
it's more of like a
um I want to say it's more of a like
company oriented thing but um still
pretty baller $4 million that's like
massive
um all right cool man so let's see where
we at okay we're we got we went down a
little uh little tangent
there contracts yeah hashtag really cool
delimiter to use it send it not through
the browser but through your your HP
proxy and try to get something to cash
incorrectly um because the back end
trunk get the path and the front end
doesn't or vice versa right um and we
see scenarios in this is hashtag a
delimiter table that he created in his
uh in his write up where some origin
servers will see it as a delimiter some
won't some caching servers will see it
as a delimiter some won't so it's like
if you can get a mismatch between the
two and there are a lot of mismatches
then if anything is being cashed then
you should be able to to do some cool uh
cash poisoning with this and cash
poisoning is like massively uh impactful
I think like I won't name any names or
call out any scenarios but I was at a
live hacking event I was talking with a
hacker that wasn't on my radar and uh
recently came on my radar and we're
talking about the vules that he found
and he's like yeah I found this cash
poisoning that did this like essentially
one of the most internet breaking things
I can possibly think of and uh and he
got some crazy bounties for it and all
because of understanding thoroughly how
to manipulate these caches so
specifically cash poisoning like I I
find webcash deception pretty often I've
not found webcash poisoning as much and
I think that's I'm sleeping on that
personally yeah it's I mean this is
awesome research so definitely going to
put this one in my in my bookmarks for
uh whenever I come across some some cash
poisoning any caching functionality
really and and and and I'll talk about
that as well here like there there are
some caching strategies I love that he
made this more concrete because it like
so much of this for me was like
intuition and like well if the caching
is happening here then this that and the
other thing but he also he built out
three categories of web cache poisoning
strategies okay um caching by extension
if the server is caching by extension
right that's we listed a bunch of
extensions earlier that um are helpful
for
this if they're caching by Static paths
so essentially everything under SL
static gets gets cached that's a common
configuration right um or if they're
caching default files so essentially
that is cloud flare by default will cach
robots.txt or like sitemap.xml or
whatever right um and so you can
potentially use those default caching
rules along with a uh a path traversal
or like a a a path um truncation with
the the hashtag to make the caching
server think that this is robot.txt that
I'm caching but it's actually SL user
account information or whatever or like
even some invalid um thing will will
Doss these end points um so very cool
stuff there um okay Joel I'm sorry one
last thing on this okay just give me
give me just one more second okay I
promise
um dot segment normalization so past
reversals the graph that I'm looking at
right now needs to be seen by the world
right I put it in the doc Joel this is
crazy right there there is so much
variance in how a path is normalized
between various different web servers
this is really eye opening to me like I
knew that this was happening at some
level but I hadn't seen how much
variance there was there's a ton of
variant um yeah I mean it's like
literally what 50/50 yeah it's 50/50
it's like like Cloud flare does not
normalize it before it passes it through
neither does Apache enginex does IAS
does cloud front does gcp doesn't uh
Puma doesn't fastly doesn't impera does
like it it's like there's so much
variant there um that that should be
exploitable I'm surprised I don't find
more dot normalization bugs yeah I mean
I will say like I think like one of the
biggest
interesting things here for me is like
just Apache versus engine X right
probably I don't know the numbers but I
would guess those are like the two most
widely used web web servers or like you
know at least somewhere in the St and
they do it differently they don't even
they're not even consistent with each
other right like of all the things that
I would expect to be consistent with
each other I would expect Apache and
engine X to be essentially mirrors of
each other and yet they are not and it's
I mean it's crazy yeah yeah and I think
that might have to do with I'm looking
at this configuration here how
how enginex deals with um like percent
2f and and stuff like that which is an
an issue that we've I exploited really
recently um and essentially Apache
requires a specific configuration to
decode percent 2f as a as a path segment
um if it's given percent 2f rather than
a slash and enginex does not so um
that's explainable in a lot of contexts
uh so definitely keep an eye out for
that anytime you're you're thinking
about how um how you may have a specific
limited path and may be able to add
things onto the end and then Traverse
back because percent 2f is is perceived
by those servers as a um as a path to
limiter yeah so interesting all right
dude uh that's all I had on gotta cash
them all uh what what do uh you got
anything else here or we moving along um
no no nothing else I do have a little I
do have a little extra thing at the end
so we yeah um are we there there are we
there are we at the yeah I mean I think
I am going to chat very briefly about
oranges right up do you want me to do
that now or or later yeah go ahead go
ahead yeah okay so last piece of
research from Defcon black hat that
we're gonna have we're going to cover
this week so essentially this is my Hit
List portswigger research and orange um
was this research by orange who just
decided I'm going to I love the quote
see if I can find this quote in here
he's like he's like yeah you know when I
do research I like to break a bunch of
stuff the most hardened stuff the stuff
that people use everywhere um and so I
said why don't I attack
Apache I was like no he says as you know
I I always aim to challenge big targets
that can impact the entire internet um
which no big deal yeah he hit hit the
nail on the head here right um and I
think he does a little uh humble Flex
later on in this uh this post where he
says uh I am now the number one holder
of Apache cves uh which is super badass
in my opinion um and the research was
really cool and stuff that I really
couldn't believe like there was
essentially he figured out a way with a
very very common um Apache configuration
to just get arbitrary file system read
and just dump it like like with and the
the payload is so simple too it's like
percent 3F uh will truncate the path in
a specific scenario and then the path
will get misinterpreted from a URL to a
file system file and then like you could
just like you can literally just write
site.com you know VAR www SL and then
just give it a full path and it'll just
or SL Etsy password it'll just dump it
it's like what is going on here that's
crazy and so I was like when I saw this
I didn't really believe it to be honest
like I was like I don't think this works
this way so I I like fired up my Apache
server whatever and of course it didn't
work that way and I and I that I was
like why is it working this way and I
was like oh I'm patched cuz they've
already pushed it and like I've updated
my Apache server um but yeah like he was
spitting out this error saying like you
need to have uh a flag you know unsafe
percent 3F or unsafe 3F or whatever and
I Google that and freaking oranges open
internet bug Bounty hacker one
disclosure report pops up saying like so
they fixed it with you know uh unsafe 3F
flag and it's just anyway really amazing
research um we've seen in the web cache
research that enginex rewrite rules have
problems with um with percent OA we've
seen here that Apache has confusions on
their rewrite rules with percent 3F the
question mark I bet that there are a lot
of weird inconsistencies with um rewrite
rules in General on on web servers
that's a great area for research for
anybody who's looking to do HTTP stack
research dude I mean per usual I I think
I don't know if I've told the story
before I don't know if I can't tell the
maybe I can't tell the story
uh one
time I'm not oh my God Joel come on
don't bait us like that you gotta
something no let me just say this let me
just say this um if you ever receive a
report from Orange yeah it's going to be
a bad day yeah I believe that I
absolutely believe that um so yeah
there's there's lots of cool stuff in
here I to be honest I'm I'm going to be
honest with you guys I read this through
once and I picked up some things but I
really honestly need to read it again
before I feel super comfortable talking
about the technical details of it the
the problem with this research right now
is it's a great read and you can see
like the methodology and like um how he
found all these things and like the
impact and be like whoa that's nuts the
problem with it is um they're patched
thank God right or else the internet
would be breaking right um and so you
know a lot of the configurations that
you're going to see are going to be
patched against this but um if you can
if you can find Apache servers that are
haven't been updated uh I think it would
be very valuable for any of the Recon
boys out there I know you you Recon boys
are listening um to essentially take a
look at how this research works and try
to create some some
um Flags some um fingerprinting for a
server that may be vulnerable to this
and then try to pop it because the
configurations that are required for
this these exploits to work are
extremely common and are even in the
Apache documentation um and so I think
it should be very doable to find
vulnerable servers that have vulnerable
configurations with this at scale if you
get creative with your um with your
nuclei templates or your scanning
environment like you're scanning modules
yeah yeah totally totally all right man
that's all I had on this one I'm not
going to go too too deep
much deeper into this one but yeah
presentent percent 3F does weird things
on Apache rewrite for sure okay so
little bit of extra interesting thing
okay um I got nerd sniped by you and
this
research um I was looking at the python
uh codex Library the built-in Library
it's called codex and uh sure enough
they have idna parsing they have puny
code parsing and wa you got you wait
hold on this is not the trusted types
thing this is not Joel what is wrong
with you man okay all right fine go tell
me about it tell me about it yes but uh
I was looking at the source code and I
think it's probably you could probably
sneak some things through there that's
what I'm thinking oh really the python
codex yeah it seems to be pretty I mean
it's just
like it yeah there doesn't seem to be
checks for those sort of conversion
maybe I mean it could be just the usage
and the use case because it seems like
puny code is basically like a separate
thing and then there's the
uh stuff for like domain names
specifically and idna will do like extra
stuff to normalize the host name or
whatever but so I'm I'm still poking at
this but um yeah I think if other
languages other implementations of the
idna idn and um puny code parsing
probably probably take it guys take it
and run with it Gareth you know that
that's the thing with these man like
reading the research is cool in doing
stuff and I was telling myself this as I
was as I was reading it I was like
reading this research is cool but at the
end of the day it's not going to do me
any good if I don't Implement any of
this so I what I told myself is I need
to go build kaido workflows to detect
some of this caching stuff I need to
actually add it to my like brain to
actually check for encoded word whenever
um I'm dealing with email-based stuff um
and I need to start paying attention
more attention to timing based stuff
when I'm I'm dealing within a a blackbox
environment where I'm trying to figure
out what's going on because I think
there is a lot of stuff that that uh a
lot of doors that can be opened by all
of those research techniques yeah um and
one other just last little interesting
tidbit is that uh they actually tell you
in the in the official documentation
from from python docop python.org if you
need the idna 2008 Standard from RFC
5891 and RFC 5895 use the third party
idna module and they just link you to a
pipie package that some some guy May
so uh just keep that in mind that also
the official docs will refer you to a uh
third party library on ppie that who
knows how that's been implemented as
well so just food for thought more
attack surface and I will certainly be
taking a look at it and I would
recommend other people to too yeah very
cool all right solid dude did you have
anything on on trusted types that you
want to talk about this week or we're
going to push that to next week no no we
got to do that next week I haven't done
a deep enough on it but I will say
trusted types API very interesting seems
like
something uh that could be useful or
potentially very dangerous I hadn't
heard of it until recently um but like
the little synopsis that they they say
is that it's basically a way for web
developers to lock down certain parts of
the Dom to avoid client side
xss um I guess mainly specifically this
seems to be for Dom Dom xss is my guess
yeah maybe reflected would fall into
this somehow but yeah um you mentioned
that that you knew a little bit about it
but hadn't done a deep dive and I
haven't done a deep enough dive so um
yeah it's very interesting I heard about
this I know that file descriptor has a
uh a tool called untrusted types which I
think helps like monitor syns for Dom
xss um that utilizes or abuses trusted
types as he says in the description so
um all right let's double click into
that a little bit more next week and
we'll uh we'll swing back around to that
yeah cool yeah sounds good all right
sounds good that's a wrap on this
episode Peace guys sir
peace and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb doow
Discord join the Discord there's lots of
great conversations and chats going on
over there and if you want to support
the show there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes amas hack along alongs exclusive
Scripts and an exclusive chat Channel
with us we'll see you there